lighting Products is not easy but in
产品照明并非易事，但在
this video I will not only explain you
这段视频中，我不仅会讲解
the basic concepts but I will also
基本概念，还会将
Implement them in different situations
其应用于不同的场景，
so that you can easily your product
以便您轻松提升产品照明效果。
these two project files are available on
这两个项目文件可在
my patreon you can get it with the link
我的 Patreon 上找到，您可以通过简介中的链接获取。
description first off why should you
首先，为什么要
learn product lighting good lighting
学习产品照明？好的照明
makes anything look amazing plus it's a
能让任何东西看起来都很棒，而且它也是一种绝佳的
great way to make money businesses need
赚钱方式。企业需要
high quality visuals for ads and online
高质量的视觉效果来制作广告和运营
stores and they're willing to pay for
网店，并且他们愿意为此付费。此外，
them on top of that it's perfect for
它还能完美地丰富
your
您的
portfolio before we move on to the basic
作品集。在讲解基本
concept let me introduce you today's
概念之前，让我先介绍一下今天的
sponsor
赞助商
vagon is a cloud computer platform which
Vagon。Vagon 是一个云计算机平台，让
gives you access to high performance
您可以访问
Cloud workstations powered by RTX
由 RTX 显卡驱动的高性能云工作站，这些工作站遍布
graphic cards anywhere in the world it
世界各地。它的
works just like your PC or laptop but
使用方式与您的 PC 或笔记本电脑类似，但速度
it's way faster and stronger you can
更快、性能更强。无论​​您使用什么设备，都可以
switch to your Cloud computer and start
切换到您的云计算机并开始
your work no matter what device you are
工作。
using let me show you its power I'm
让我来展示一下它的强大功能。我现在正在
running my heaviest project on vagon
Vagon 上运行我目前最复杂的项目，
right now it has 4K textures with Max
它使用了 4K 纹理和最高
subdivisions and just look at how fast
细分级别，看看它的渲染速度有多快！
even Clinton Jones who organizes big 3D
就连组织大型 3D 挑战赛的 Clinton Jones 也
challenges has shared his reviews about
分享了他对 Vagon 的评价。
the service and it's perfect use the
这项服务非常完美，点击
link in the description to sign up today
描述中的链接即可立即注册，
and boost your workflow with a fast
用高速工作站提升您的工作效率。
workstation so the basic concept I use
我使用的基本概念
is to light the product from three sides
是从三个方向照亮产品：从
a strong intensity light from the back
背面照射一束强光，营造强烈的高光；
highlights a sharp light from one side
从一侧照射一束锐利的光线，
which will create some interesting
营造有趣的
shadows and a soft light from the other
阴影；以及从
side of the sharp light which will light
锐利光线的另一侧照射一束柔和的光线，照亮
the main product there are more things
产品主体。当然，还有更多技巧，
like if you are lighting something like
例如，如果您要照亮
glass you will need to use more
玻璃之类的物体，则需要使用更多
techniques and you don't have to worry
方法。您不必担心，
about it because I will explain you
因为我会解释
everything I
我所
know Theory will only take you so far so
知道的一切。理论知识只能帮您到此为止，所以
let's just start the Practical work I am
我们直接开始实践吧。我
using this keyboard from sketch Fab so
使用的是 SketchFab 的这款键盘，因此在
product before you start lighting your
开始为场景打光之前，您需要设置好相机和产品。
scene in my case I have already added a
在我的例子中，我已经添加了
camera and I have also rotated the
相机，并且旋转了
keyboard to give it a little d dnamic
键盘，使其更具动感。
touch I always start with the highlights
我总是从高光开始，
add an area light and move it to the
添加一个区域光并将其移动到
back of your product it is better to
产品的背面。最好
open a small window where you can see
打开一个小窗口，以便查看
the render
渲染
view you will have to increase the
视图。您需要增加
intensity of the area light don't
区域光的强度，但不要
increase it too much a value like this
增加太多。 这样就可以了。
will work now for the sharp light I
对于强光，我
usually place it on the side opposite to
通常把它放在
where the product is
产品
facing before you add another area light
正面的反面。在添加另一个区域光之前，
make sure to move the 3D cursor to the
确保将 3D 光标移动到
center of your product you can do that
产品的中心。
in two ways select your product and
有两种方法可以做到这一点：选择产品，然后
press shift plus s and select move 3D
按 Shift + S，选择“将 3D
cursor to active mesh or you can just
光标移动到活动网格”；或者，您可以
press shift and right click why we are
按住 Shift 键并单击鼠标右键。这样
doing this is so that we can rotate the
做是为了
light around the product easily change
方便我们围绕产品旋转光源。将此
this option to 3D cursor and now
选项更改为“3D 光标”。现在
duplicate the back light and press R
复制背光，然后按
twice to rotate it around the product
两次 R 键使其围绕产品旋转。将其放置
place it at the side of the product
在产品的侧面，
decrease the intensity and to make this
降低强度，为了使光线更
sharper decrease the spread value what
锐利，降低扩散值。这样做会将
it does is that it sharpens the light by
光线
focusing on one point I like to keep it
聚焦在一个点上，从而使光线更锐利。我喜欢保持这种设置，
like this so that it creates hard
因为它能产生硬朗的
Shadows now we need one more light to
阴影。现在我们需要另一个光源来
complete the setup duplicate this area
完成设置。复制这个区域
light and rotate it
光并将其旋转
180° you can simply type 180 on your
180°。您可以直接在键盘上输入 180，
keyboard or manually rotate it increase
或者手动旋转。增加
the spread of the light and you are good
光线扩散值，就完成了。
to go this works great for products that
这种方法非常适合
are not glossy things get rough in that
非光泽产品。在这种情况下，产品表面会变得粗糙，
scenario but I have got a solution for
但我有解决办法，稍后
that and I will cover that in the video
我会解释。 视频里会讲解这一点，
so sit back and watch the complete
所以请放松观看完整
video area lights are sharp and because
视频。区域光很锐利，因此
of that Reflections look terrible you
反射效果很糟糕。你
can use an image texture like this to
可以使用像这样的图像纹理来
fix this issue you can get these two
解决这个问题。你可以
images for free on my patreon the link
在我的 Patreon 上免费获取这两张图片，链接
is in description it's simple to use
在视频描述里。使用方法很简单：
open the Shader editor and check use
打开着色器编辑器，勾选“使用
notes add an image texture and open the
注释”，添加图像纹理，然后打开
image that you have downloaded from my
你从我的 Patreon 下载的图片。
patreon you can also use an image like
你也可以使用像
this and the process is
这样的图片，操作步骤
similar lighting glass is a whole other
类似。玻璃的照明完全是另一
story yet the position and rotation of
回事，但灯光的位置和旋转方式
Lights is similar we actually won't use
类似。我们实际上不会使用
area lights because they are sharp and
区域光，因为它们很锐利，
have horrible Reflections what we will
反射效果很差。我们将
use is planes with an emission Shader
使用带有渐变节点的发射着色器的平面。
with a gradient node let's start with
让我们从之前处理
the same steps we did with the keyboard
键盘的步骤开始。
I am using this bottle from the blender
我使用的是 Blender Kit 库中的这个瓶子。
kit Library I have tweaked a lot of
我调整了很多
material settings to make it look good
材质设置，让它看起来更好。
add a plane move it to the back open the
添加一个平面，将其移动到后面。打开
Shader editor and delete the principled
着色器编辑器，删除 Principled
Shader add an emission node and connect
着色器。添加一个发射节点，并将
it to the material output increase the
其连接到材质输出。将强度增加到
strength to something you like you will
你喜欢的程度。
get a problem here unlike the area
这里会遇到一个问题，与区域
lights these will be visible in the
光不同，这些平面在渲染中是可见的。 将
render to hide the plane from camera go
平面从摄像机中隐藏，
into the object tab go under the
进入对象选项卡，在
visibility Tab and uncheck the camera
可见性选项卡下取消选中摄像机。
you can now play with the strength of
现在您可以调整
the emission and make sure to not go too
发光强度，但请确保不要设置得
high with this Val Val scale it
太高。再次
according to your
根据您的
product again move the 3D cursor to the
产品缩放。按 Shift + S 将 3D 光标移动到
center of your product with shift plus s
产品中心。
duplicate the back light and position it
复制背光并将其放置
on the side of the
在
product remove the backlight material
产品侧面。移除背光材质
and create a new material add an
并创建一个新材质。添加一个发光节点和
emission node and a gradient node with a
一个渐变节点，并添加
texture mapping and coordinate node
纹理映射和坐标节点。
connect the nodes like this change these
像这样连接节点。更改这些
values to rotate the gradient add a
值以旋转渐变。添加一个
color ramp and change it to spline drag
颜色渐变并将其更改为样条曲线。拖动
it and make something soft like
它并使其呈现柔和的效果，像
this make sure the bright side goes to
这样。确保明亮的一面朝向
the back of the product you can rotate
产品的背面。您可以将
it 180° on its axis this will create a
其绕轴旋转 180°。这将
smooth Fade Out in the glossy material
在光泽材质中创建一个平滑的淡出效果，效果非常好。
and it works like a charm you can
您可以
increase the strength but again don't go
增加强度，但同样不要设置得
too high duplicate it and move it to the
太高。复制它并将其移动到另一
side I like to rotate it a bit to create
侧。我喜欢稍微旋转一下，以获得像
this so now you know how this works but
这样的好效果。现在您知道它是如何工作的了，但
I still have one last thing to tell
我还有最后一点要告诉
you when you add a ground like I did for
您：当您像我在
this render you will run into a problem
此渲染中一样添加地面时，您会遇到…… 问题是
the lights will destroy the reflections
灯光会破坏
on the ground what you can do is use
地面的反射。你可以使用
light linking it's very simple just
灯光链接功能，非常简单。只需
select the light go into this tab and
选择灯光，进入此选项卡，
under here you will find the light
即可找到灯光
linking option it is pretty hidden yet
链接选项。它隐藏得比较隐蔽，但功能却非常强大。
it works like a gem create a new light
创建一个新的灯光
Link and drag your products or objects
链接，然后将你想要灯光影响的产品或物体拖放到该链接中。
that you want the light to effect I have
我已经为
created this for every light and this is
每个灯光都创建了链接，这就是
the final result I have also used my
最终效果。我还使用了我的
cinematic compositor for both of these
电影合成器来
renders and you can see how it turns
渲染这两个场景，你可以看到它是如何将原本
boring sharp renders into soft
生硬的渲染图变成柔和
good-looking renders you should give it
美观的渲染图的。你应该
a try link is in
尝试一下，链接在
description let's do a quick recap
描述中。我们快速回顾一下：
lighting products is simple you just
产品照明很简单。你
have to add a strong light in the
只需在背景中添加一个强光
background to create strong highlights
来创建强烈的高光；
you have to use another light with less
你需要使用另一个
spread value to create sharp Shadow you
扩散值较低的灯光来创建清晰的阴影；你
have to use one more light with high
需要使用另一个
spread value if you are lighting
扩散值较高的灯光。如果你要照亮
something like glass use planes with
玻璃之类的物体，请使用带有
gradient texture you have to make sure
渐变纹理的平面。你必须确保
this side is outside and you hide it in
这一面朝外，并在相机中将其隐藏。
the camera you can also use the light
你还可以使用灯光
linking feature to only light your
链接功能只照亮你的
product thanks for watching the video
产品。感谢观看视频，
and you can get both of these project
你可以
files from my patreon and to make things
在我的 Patreon 上获取这两个项目文件。 为了让体验
better you can grab some free stuff too
更棒，你还可以
from my patreon subscribe
从我的 Patreon 订阅中获得一些免费内容。